[Music]
he
w
[Music]
hello everybody and welcome to the askab
show episode
204 I hope you're all doing great and
today's episode is going to be an
episode in which I will take questions
from the comments questions that you
have asked in the comments I'm going to
take a bunch of those and once that is
done I will take more questions from the
live chat so as always before we begin
let me see who all is there let me greet
you all I can see the world is one
geopolitical dub niharika Gupta shinchan
Samurai Batman LJ Singh SLC arou arush
Sinha J sing thees hello PR VP gorov
Captain Rogers archan Panda some
Amisha Mishra hello vikrant marate
dungar Singh Chan let's go shingar pram
samit statement Rish Singh bimla s by
Tushar kalbur kalburgi Ashish
vishwakarma Dr suak dager random skull
ruir solanki prian Su feminist Slayer
shiat the ancient Indian astrologer
Alexa YK Martian panage 49 Arian ajar
kjan Pari Krishna Anar JN Singh hello
braish Sharma adri Aditi hello sub suas
Goda TM AI Roy vidan Singh utar Zed J
har taker agba mukad hello zuban eong
good evening rishab Singh Vishnu mohanan
Harish Shankar deep deep dat Sati Chan
adz Ahmed anant Pai anurag J guman vinit
Mishra anit CSC pay three ways S2 AI Roy
and everybody else I can go on forever
but I think we should get going with the
questions threeways S2 has finally
joined College fantastic all the best do
very well
sir or ma'am depending mcloven Raj Singh
everybody else Mand space KGB agent
hi okay let's take some questions we're
going to talk about mainly see I get as
always lots tons of questions every week
today I'm going to focus see there's a
lot of stuff happening in the world
right now right so I'm going to focus a
little bit more on what's Happening
currently today I won't take any history
questions so apologies to those of you
who asked questions about history but
today I'm going to focus mainly on two
major things two major themes one is the
Olympics we're going to take a few
questions about that India's performance
is something that is a lot is being
spoken about and secondly about the
situation the coup in our neighboring
country of East Pakistan Bangladesh so
we're going to talk about these things
mostly today and then I will take
questions from the live chat in which
you can ask whatever you want I'll take
as many of those as I can so let's go
with the first
question okay that's two questions in
one Rick data and Jil
chandarana is the Olympics a waste of
time for India even after so much
support from the government of India the
performance was pathetic even smaller
countries is performed better than India
where do we lack and we have very few
medals in the Olympics what what do you
think is the main reason behind this the
dumb education system that never gives
importance to sports and other
activities or is it the less importance
giv to given by Indian parents to sports
why is it that India doesn't do well so
for
example look yeah you're right we get so
few medals in the Olympics tiny
countries get more medals yesterday I
saw uh girl from from Thailand win a
medal in Taekwondo or some S I think it
was ta kwondo many smaller Nations get
medals better medals than India I think
yesterday today when was it this is
Pakistani Javin thrower who got the gold
ahead of our guy who got the silver the
the defending Olympic gold medalist came
second this time our guy um so why is it
that this
happens uh what is the name of our guy
the the the
javalin
thrower I don't know why I keep
forgetting his
name uh
javalin through
India his name n Chopra N choa I
apologize I keep forgetting his name so
my question is why do we Depend and
these are very legitimate questions that
are being asked right now and we have
just a handful of people who are
actually capable of getting medals most
of the athletes we have sent probably
weren't capable of really having a
realistic chance of getting a medal PB
synu
disappointing um n Chopra yes we know
what happened there was the old VES fot
thing and so much so on so forth but
most of the athletes apparently did not
have much of a chance of getting a gold
uh H what's her name H sidu I think the
lady who got two bronzes he did well but
my question is we depend on a handful of
people who are our medal hopes why don't
we have a pool of 500 Nita chobra level
athletes why why don't we have that what
is preventing us from finding a handful
or more than a handful of worldclass
athletes from a pool of 1.4 billion
people what is preventing us
and Gil chander speaks about the
education system right that doesn't give
importance to sports and other
activities I think the education system
it's okay if it do give importance to
sports I think that the
sporting the desire for doing sports is
something that is innate in all of us
and it's kind of an extracurricular
activity my point is
this there is a significant parallel
between the Indian education system and
India's sporting establishment which is
entirely set up by the government I have
said this multiple times those who are
familiar with me will know my views
about the Indian education system and
one of its major defining
characteristics of the Indian education
system is that it excels at identifying
talent and destroying talent and it also
excels at promoting
mediocrity so the education system is
designed to identify and Destroy Talent
it is designed to promote mediocrity
that is what it is designed to do and
the same I would say can be said of the
Indian sporting establishment the
various
institutions
look in the government of India there
are certain Ministries that are doing
really well the finance ministry I I
know what people have to say about the
tax regime and all but overall it's been
doing well the road transport Railways
Ministry they are ramping up
infrastructure
Etc uh I can think of the foreign
Ministry is a good example it's doing
really really well the core Ministries
that come Direct essentially under the
pmo they are doing really well but there
are a large number of Ministries that
are doing very
poorly one example is the culture
Ministry one of the worst performing
Ministries in in all of India and
another another example could be the
sports Ministry I mean if you look at
the the Hall of medals that we've got in
the this these Olympic Games it's an
indicator of the extremely poor
performance of the sporting Ministry
Sports Ministry out of a huge pool of
1.4 billion people you could not not
even get us 20 medalists or even like
five gold medalists something is wrong
so the the solution is not to Simply
throw more money at the problem and hope
that the money will solve the problem
now if you have an
institution that is structurally
deficient and it is designed to destroy
talent and reward mediocrity then the
more money you throw at it the more
mediocrity it will promote and the more
Talent it will destroy do you understand
that so what you need is reforms deep
structural reforms in these
institutions we know very well of
various sporting institutions in
India U for example with respect to
certain Sports
football various Sports
institutions that are allegedly run by
vested interests and have no interest in
the in the upliftment of the sport in
the
country I think it's very well known how
things have been for
decades so when you have an association
a sport Association or a sports in
institution whose objective apparent I
mean we know that if you have a
government body that that is catering to
a certain sport its objective is to is
to uplift that sport in the country to
promote the sport in the country and
internationally and to find the right
talent and and promote them right so
that India does well that's the
objective but
these uh associations institutions Etc
they actually do the opposite there is
allegedly allegedly allegedly a
tremendous amount of corruption
allegedly in many of these
alleged associations and whatnot uh
there is no emphasis on on Merit
mediocrity is rewarded allegedly
allegedly uh connections are rewarded
and whatnot this is known to to
allegedly happen allegedly all of the
time allegedly allegedly I think we all
know this and this is called
corruption
right so why hasn't the government in
the past 10 years I forget about the
past 70
years this particular government why
haven't they addressed this in the past
10 years I know that other things are
more important the defense of the
country is important the economy is
important infrastructure is important
but you have these Ministries and
ministers who are appointed over here to
take care of this and you have a
significant amount of money that is
already being poured into these
Ministries then you might as well run
them
properly so why is that not being
done I am still of the opinion that the
current government is the best
government we've had in the past 70
years 75 80 whatever years so imagine
how bad things were before this at least
now we get a small clutch of medals
earlier it was impossible for Indians to
get medals we had like three medals in s
in 50 years or something now every
Olympic Games we get a few medals and
this time Hall has been poorer than the
last time that's why everyone is
disappointed it is very disappointing so
my point my point is very
clear the lots of the sporting
associations Etc institutions whatever
you want to call them I will not go into
the names most of these are run are
mismanaged allegedly most of these are
allegedly mismanaged most of these are
allegedly deeply allegedly
corrupt okay allegedly one hears all
kinds of reports in the media you look
it up you'll find it so why has this not
been addressed is my question there is
no dir of talent in this
country why can't we identify 500 n
chopras i i don't blame the guy for n
Chopra for for not coming first this
time he has never crossed he has never
thrown the javelin
Beyond 90 meters his his career best is
slightly below 90 metters see n Chopra
has a specific kind of physique he's an
EXT extremely flexible individual he's
like a whet you know you can you can
Flex him as much as you want it'll
release the like a like a like a coiled
spring that is the kind of physique he
has and that's how he's able to reach
close to 90 MERS through with with his
jablin throw but there is another kind
of physique that also exists it is a Le
less flexible in individual who is built
like a bull and that's what the
Pakistani fellow is who came first we
have plenty of these people in India
construction workers ricksha drivers
whatnot we have them all over the
country but we don't tap into that pool
of talent so we should have various
kinds of physics at our disposal in
javelin throw in in every sport the
flexible physique the bull bullish
physique everything and let them compete
but we don't do that
so the problem is the government of
India it's doing better in the past 10
years than before than ever before but
it is not doing enough it is not doing
enough that is the story of the country
overall India has so much incredible
potential you know some people will
complain about Indian genetics being
poor like 30 years ago when I was a kid
I was speaking to somebody just now on
on on WhatsApp and we were discussing
this and I I haven't responded to your
latest message I'll do that after this
live
stream so 30 years ago I remember when I
was a kid or a teenager or whatever it
was it was said that Indians can never
produce fast borers Indians are just
genetically inferior right that's what
we were always told now the last two
test series that we had in Australia on
Australian soil we defeated the
Australians both times with a superior
fast bowling attack our fast Bowlers
performed better than the Australian
fast Bowlers and the Australian fast
bowling attack is the best in the world
right now well second to us obviously
clearly in both these Series so this
entire genetic argument is is is
nonsense it's being it's been
debunked okay and if you look at the
average physique of the average Indian
man or a average Indian woman you
compare that with the average physique
of the average man or woman in some
Eastern Asian country I'll tell you the
Indians are more robust and larger but
these nations they outperform us all the
time it's because they have got their
act together and I'll tell you what
sports is extremely important for a
country it is not a waste of time or
money sporting achievements bring the
country together they unify the country
nothing succeeds and nothing unifies the
country like success it brings in this
outpouring of national
pride and you have all these divisive
forces in the country who will have to
keep quiet when when our our athletes do
well in sports
and it also is an extremely potent uh
you know it's something that increases a
Prestige internationally globally a
nation that that may be poor but
performs Super relatively at sports for
example Jamaica everybody admires that
country thanks to you people like usin
bolt Etc so there are so many such
examples but and that's why countries
like China countries like the former
USSR like the former East Germany Etc
they invested so much in
sports and in India yeah the money may
be there to some extent but how is it
being allegedly misused that's the point
my point is the government needs to get
its act together I don't blame the
athletes I don't blame n Chopra I don't
blame vinesh fogot I don't blame whoever
may have performed not performed CNU
whoever we need a 100 times more
athletes of the same caliber we have
them all over the place but we don't we
don't promote them we don't identify and
and them and give them the right kind of
uh resources needed to succeed
no that's the problem it's it's the same
story as the Indian education system
exactly the same story The
stakeholders should be the athletes and
the population of India but the actual
stakeholders unfortunately are the
people who run the associations and
organizations just like the education
system where the stakeholders should be
the students of the country and the
citizens of the country but the actual
stakeholders the ones who are protected
are the educational you know the the
academic and non-academic staff just a
rotten system I wonder when the
government of India will start looking
into these matters because I think
they've had 10 years of they've done
nothing they have definitely been the
best government in the past 70 years 80
years but they could have done so much
more it is a a clear case of incredibly
huge Mist opportunities and it is so
frustrating so frustrating
sahil patil says is it possible that the
tournament that a tournament like the
Olympics is also controlled by the US
given what happened with VES fot whose
gold medal match was with the US
Contender yes our girl vinesh was
disqualified uh yeah and but the
question is interesting is it possible
that the US
controls um a tournament like the
Olympics so let me
um put something on this
screen yeah let's let's let's share this
this uh article put out by the world
anti-doping Association wada
wada huh let's see what it says this
released on the 7th of August 2024 today
is the 9th of August this came out 48
hours ago W statement on reuter story
exposing usada scheme in contravention
of world anti-doping code let's read
this it's a short article
the world anti-doping agency W response
to reuter story of 7th August 2024
exposing a scheme whereby the US anti-
doping doping agency usada allowed
athletes who had doped to compete for
years in at in at least one case without
ever publishing or sanctioning their
anti-doping rule violations in direct
contravention of the world anti-doping
code and usada's own rules this usara
scheme threatened the Integrity of
sporting competition by which the code
seeks to protect by operating it the
United States anti-doping agency was in
clear breach of the rules contrary to
the claims made by usada gu did not sign
off on this practice by permitting drug
cheats to compete for years on the
promise that they would try to obtain
incriminating evidence against others
within the code there's a provision
whereby an athlete who provides
substantial assistance in incriminating
other cheats can subsequently apply to
have a proportion of their period of
ineligibility suspended however there's
a clear process for that which does not
involve allowing Those Who Have Cheated
to continue to compete while they may or
may not gather incriminating evidence
against others and while they could
retain a performance enhancement effect
from the substances they took from the
illegal substances they took when V
eventually found out about this
non-compliant practice in 2021 many
years after it had started it
immediately instructed usada to desist
wada is now aware of at least three
cases where athletes who had committed
serious anti-doping rule violations
American athletes were allowed to
continue to compete for years while they
acted allegedly as undercover as agents
for the US antidoping agency without it
notifying W and without there being any
provision allowing such a practice under
the code of under the code or usada's
own rules
in one case an elite level athlete who
competed at Olympic qualifier in
international events in the United
States admitted to taking steroids and
EO and yet was continued was permitted
to continue competing all the way up to
retirement their case was never
published results never disqualified
prize money never returned and no
suspension was ever served the athlete
was allowed to line up against their
unknowing competitors as they had never
cheated in that case when usada
eventually admitted to Vada what had
been going on it advised that any
publication of consequences or
disqualification of results would put
the athletes security at risk and asked
W to agree to
non-publication and so on so forth so
the athletes doping was therefore never
made public in other another case of a
high level athlete usada never notified
Vada of its decision to lift an athletes
provisional suspension which is an
appealable decision despite being
required to do so under the code had V
been notified it would never have
allowed this how must other athletes
feel knowing that they were competing in
good faith against those who were known
by usada to have cheated it is ironic
and hypocritical that the US anti-doping
agency Association cries foul when it
suspects other anti-doping associations
organizations of not following the rules
to the letter while it did not announce
doping cases for years and allowed
cheats to carry on competing on the off
chance that they might help them catch
whatever blah blah blah wada wonders if
the usada board of directors which
governs usada or the US Congress which
funds it knew about this non-compliant
practice that not only undermine the
Integrity of sporting competition but
also put the cooperating athletes
security at
risk you get
it the United States are the world's
biggest drug cheats when it comes to
sporting
tournaments this is clear now and they
routinely accuse Nations like China of
and Russia Etc of of of being cheats the
biggest cheats in the world so this is
this is the double standard you are the
biggest cheat and to cover that up you
accuse everybody else of being
cheats so yes it is well known that the
powerful Nations the Nations that are
powerful geopolitically also control
everything else in the world this is
called Soft power and soft power doesn't
work unless you have hard power if the
US was not this big superpower do you
think it could get away with all these
things of course it would never get away
with all these things that tells you
that the amount of control and influence
the US has over the Olympics or over
usada Vada whatever sporting
competitions the over the world and all
that it would not be possible without
the us being a genuine Global superpower
power so yes no doubt about it there's
cheating all over the place in the US is
the biggest sporting cheat most of these
us athletes are cheats they take
steroids up to the gills have you heard
of flojo Florence Griffith Joiner she I
think she won Gold in 88 soul soul
Olympics she was what she was glorified
as this great greatest athlete of all
time and all a few years a few years
later she's
dead she's dead in her youth in the
prime of her life because of all the
steroids and what not she took happens
over and over again so many US athletes
have been exposed and I and clearly now
from after reading the article it's
clear that way many way more athletes
have never ever been exposed and the US
uh anti-doping associ Association usada
knows this and they are extremely
complicit in this and it is funded by
the US Congress so this goes all the way
to the top cheats all over the
place there you have
it balam Putin says do you think Indian
athletes are being discriminated against
in the Olympics just to demoralize the
nation and make us realize that you are
no one so like I said the US controls
the US essentially controls the sporting
establishments in the world Olympics Etc
and there are so many examples of
cheating uh happening against Indians uh
and not just Indians other countries too
I remember in the uh in the London
Olympics 2012 I had watched a few of the
boxing matches there was this Japanese
guy called shatzi satosi Shimizu Satoshi
I know this name Satoshi is very famous
these days for crypto reasons but
Satoshi Shimizu let's let's let's put
that on the
screen okay this guy this Japanese guy
boxer
satosi
Shimizu so he has a fight against
somebody okay
satosi
Shu uh 2012
olymics so
um see referee sent home after sh satosi
satosi
satosi Shimizu wins appeal so this guy
this boxer he knocked down his opponent
like 15 I don't know how many
times like I remember he had knocked the
guy down at least five or six times what
does it say six
times so the guy who Satoshi Shibu
knocks down six times that guy
wins that is clear that is a clear case
of of the referee cheating and it was so
blatant that they had to send the
referee home so in this case the the I
mean in Justice was done but there have
been so many cases about in which India
has been cheated upon and nothing has
been done this Olympics 2024 Olympics
Paris Olympics
hockey uh India played the UK the what
great allegedly Great Britain in the
quarterfinal I believe and the match
went to a penalty shootout
right
and during the penalty shootout the
English goalkeeper
was surreptitiously referring referring
to an iPad he had access to an iPad
while the penalty shoot out was was
happening and he was checking data and
information about each Indian player and
how to deal with them on the
iPad the guy should have been banned for
life for this blatant cheating the team
should have been disqualified nothing
happened are we talking about something
that happened like 3 4 days ago there is
blatant cheating in sports at
International level at the highest level
and the weaker a nation you are
geopolitically or the more people are
annoyed with you geopolitically the more
you'll be targeted in sporting events so
India has refused to to the line of the
West and Ukraine and very other things
and India has been
supporting shik Casina against the US in
Bangladesh so India will be punish for
all these things in a variety of ways
including in sports so yes there is
discrimination against India I remember
there was discrimination in the Beijing
Olympics against India against various
other athletes of other countries by the
Chinese blatant discrimination so this
happens on a routine basis it's not just
about India it's about many other
nations that are discriminated against
but India gets a little bit of a of
special treatment these days yes there
is discrimination no doubt about it you
will see that in badminton you will see
that in almost all sports cheating
discrimination okay okay VES we have to
talk about talk about vesh rajat Chopra
Sun Moon and
cile did the Olympics Federation cheat
with vin fogat did they rob her of the
gold medal steams
fishy what's the conspiracy behind the
disqualification of our wrestler vinesh
fogat uh we could have won a goal
otherwise uh what do you think of the
disqualification of vines fogot from the
finals of the 50 kilogram wrestling in
the Olympics the way she beat Japan's
number one wrestler and then the
semi-final win over Cuba she could have
won the gold who is it fault is it the
dietician the coaches or somebody from
outside thank you thank you okay so
that's the thing so what happened is
that uh vesh fogat was found to be about
100 grams above the 50 kilogram limit
and as a result of that she was
disqualified so there are weight classes
in Combat Sports contact Sports Combat
Sports like wrestling Boxing Etc and the
these weight limits are Justified I mean
if there were no weight limits then you
would have a situation in which somebody
who like 110 kilograms has will fight
somebody who 50 kilograms that is a
horrible mismatch right so you need
weight categories so in in ladies
wrestling there is 50 kilogram category
there's a 53 kilogram category and so on
so forth so VES originally used to
compete at the 53 kilogram category but
for this particular Olympic Games she
has competed at the 50 kilogram category
now for most people gaining weight
losing weight is not a big deal you just
eat a lot of stuff to gain like three
kilos in a week's time or if you want to
lose three kilos in a week's time you
kind of go on a starvation diet like a
th calorie diet for a week and you will
come down to to that level but for
athletes who are typically at any given
point in time at the prime of their
condition in Prime
condition gaining or losing 3 kilog is a
huge deal if you are at 50 kilg and you
are a top athlete and you want to reach
and you want to compete in the 53
kilogram category you're going to have
to put on 3 kilograms of muscle mass
mostly muscle mass and that's hard
enough for a guy I forget about a girl
so going up a weight category is quite
difficult it takes time John Jones in
MMA went away for three years to move
from light heavyweight to heavyweight in
mixed martial arts UFC we went away for
three years it took him a lot of lifting
Etc and change of Lifestyle to move up
to the heavyweight category now to come
down from a from a higher category also
is just as difficult you've got to lose
muscle mass mainly muscle mass because
you already quite lean as an athlete so
you got to lose three kilos of muscle
mass in such a way that you don't lose
too much strength and that process
typically takes a year or two even if
it's just a question of three kilos
that's how tough things are at the
highest level in athletics and this girl
vesh she had about I don't know few
months to come down to 50 kilos so I
think it was already quite tough for her
to do that I'm sure the dietitians and
doctors and whoever else Sports
Nutrition practitioners and whoever the
whole team would have advised her helped
her out in
this but at the end of the day this is
what happened she got disqualified
because she was about 100 grams
overweight and she apparently tried to
cut that weight all throughout the night
through variety of means but it didn't
work so who's at fault is it V's fault
to decide to come down one weight
category is it the dietitians fault the
coaches fault the the the the
bureaucrats who run the Athletics
associations or whatever whose fault is
this my my first question would be and
and she was not overweight only for the
final match by 100 grams she was above
the 50 kilogram weight limit even when
she started the initial rounds in the
Olympics so why was she not disqualified
right away why was she allowed to
progress all the way to the final and
then disqualified by the Olympic
Association that's the first question I
would raise let's say she messed up the
association the Indian establishment
messed up the dietitians Co coaches
everybody messed up so why wasn't she
disqualified on the first day without
allowing her to and she would she should
not not have been allowed to fight a
single
bout if they allow her to fight all the
way and reach the final then how can
they disqualify her that that point and
send her home without a medal something
very WR here so I'm not really sure who
is genuinely at fault I I I would be the
last person to try and blame the girl
right now vesh okay she must have gone
through a horrible heartbreak because of
what happened
uh I'm sure there is some kind of
mistake at various
levels but the athlete typically should
have the benefit of the best advice
right from the coaches from the
dietitians from the Olympic Association
Indian Olympic Association and whoever
you I I would be the last person to
blame her for whatever happened and I'm
not getting into the politics of the
whole matter I'm not talking about that
okay so I don't know who has messed up I
think it's early days but my question
would be straight at the Paris Olympics
organizers the international Olympics
Association wrestling Association
whatever why was she not disqualified
the moment you found out she is above
the 50 kilogram weight limit she should
not have been allowed to to fight a
single bout that way this entire
heartbreak would not have
happened you should not have allowed to
reach the final and then cender home
without a medal I think something is
very fishy here
definitely okay next question is a
couple of questions payman 6 163 and
historical Marvels one how do you look
at India's aspiration to hold the 2036
Olympics in Ahmedabad will it be an
economic disaster for India should India
really host the Olympics it may bring
Prestige to the nation but may cause an
economic crisis we may not even get post
Olympics benefits like FDI because
Olympics is only a marketing strategy
and until we correct our fundamentals
like import Duty land acquisition Etc
it'll just be a waste we can
alternatively invest in better
Alternatives like making movies like
Hollywood or better
media okay I am seeing a quite a few of
these questions it looks like there is
this this narrative being spun
that India should not host should not
aspire to host Olympics in the future
because apparently it will be an
economic disaster I don't know who has
created this narrative and who is behind
this why should it be an economic
disaster how will it hurt the country
economically I can think back of the of
Olympic Games in the past 50 years 70
years and some of them succeeded
spectacularly some of them did not do
very well but none of those Olympic
Games was a disaster for the host
country economic disaster yeah in some
cases for example the World Cup that
happened recently in Qatar I believe or
wherever it was football World Cup those
stadiums that they built will not really
have much use in the future so it's kind
of a sunk
investment you know you invested all
these million hundreds of millions of
dollars in building the stadiums and it
was just for a handful of matches and in
the future nobody will use them much
it's kind of a waste of money but it's
not a disaster for the
nation imagine you spend a couple of
billion
dollars okay on an Olympic
Games and uh all that infrastructure
that you build you never use it again
after the games are over is that a
national disaster is it for a nation of
India's size and scale it's
nothing you know imagine that you have a
fictitious hypothetical country
a billion plus population5 trillion
economy $4 trillion economy okay
completely hypothetical example of a
hypothetical nation and they built an
they build an aircraft carrier which
cost them $2 billion and then that ship
sinks is it a disaster for the country
it's kind of a setback it's unfortunate
and people will feel bad about that it's
not a disaster for the nation by any
means so the in the worst case scenario
all this infrastructure structure that
you build will not be used much and it
will not serve the nation much it'll
just slowly crumble away that's the
worst case scenario even that is not an
economic disaster for the country from
which the country cannot recover it's no
big deal we spend much more money in
mandrea and God knows what schemes most
of which is wasted money okay so I don't
understand this thing and on on the on
the flip side if you look at the pros if
we get our act together by 2036
if we get our processes of import Duty
land land acquisition Etc we get our
sporting establishment all of that you
know under control and if we set things
right then it can be a gigantic Boon for
the country it's not just about
Prestige it's about creating momentum
for the
country so I think we should aspire to
hold the Olympics in India Amad I
believe is the city that's supposed to
be the that is in contention I hope we
win and I I hope we get it I don't
understand okay I'm not aware of who has
been creating spinning these narratives
but I'm seeing these questions crop up
off late which is what makes me think
that somehow somewhere someone is
spinning some narratives that this is
bad for India I don't get it I don't
think it's a waste I think it's it's
something great and if you do it right
it can be something that serves us for a
very long time so we will have to build
a lot of stadiums new stadiums land we
have plenty of land there's no question
of shortage of land in the country we
have plenty of
land we need to build a number of
stadiums the Olympic class stadiums if
it's in Amad you have to build the all
the infrastructure in that area but then
in the future Amad can serve as a
sporting center for the country so I
don't see why why there's something
wrong with it so I disagree with the
with these narratives that are being
spun by whoever I think India should
certainly bid
for the Olympics and I hope we win the
bid and we host the Olympics
2036 okay now we go on to geopolitics
enough of
sports an says is the US really a
declining power with such a huge
disparity in hard power the global order
doesn't seem to be changing anytime soon
yeah people say that the say that the US
has a declining power what is the truth
is the US a declining power so I think
people are confused influence and
power people are conf getting confused
about what power really
means what is the truest and rawest form
of power what is
power influence and power what's the
difference let's say I have I've said
this before but let me give the example
again let's say I have a million
subscribers on
YouTube that makes me influential sure
it means that a million people plus are
interested in some way or the other in
what I have to say and maybe some of
what I say may have some impact on them
and may somehow modify their behavior to
a c certain nextt okay but will those
people obey me if I ask them to do this
or that okay stand up everybody and do
the disco dance will you obey me you'll
laugh at me or let's say I say tomorrow
morning everybody needs to get a crew
cut first thing in the morning will you
obey me no you laugh at laugh at me
because it's stupid so that is influence
it has limits what is power if I
actually had power over all of you
and North Korea let's say Kim Jong own
has a ask Kim live stream and everybody
in South Korea North Korea is mandated
mandated to watch the live stream live
stream and in the live stream ask Kim
Kim Jong-un says tomorrow morning
everybody gets a crew cut now everybody
will get a crew cut first thing tomorrow
morning that is
power it's the power to make people obey
things and to give you a genuinely raw
form of power raw definition of power
power is the ability to unleash
violence on demand and that the larger
the scale of violence that can unleash
and the larger the kinds of different
violence you can unleash the more
powerful you are now the US has more
than a more than eight 800 extra
territorial military bases all across
the world the US can intervene anywhere
in the world at 60 minutes notice
intervene militarily unleash violence
anywhere in the world it's 60 minutes
notice that is the true definition of a
super superpow is that power declining
they recently changed the regime did a
regime change operation right in India
India's backyard Bangladesh they've
converted Bangladesh back into East
Pakistan they will soon acquire a new
military base in St Mar Island does that
look like a declining power it looks
like an expanding power to me what is
declining is US Prestige and US
influence because of social media the US
and its nefarious schemes regime change
operations all of that have been exposed
are being routinely exposed in real time
so that's why the image of the nation of
the United States is suffering their
Prestige to some extent is suffering
their images people are getting a more
negative uh view of the US more and more
people have this more negative view of
the US because of because of all the
truths that have that have emerged over
social media without social media none
of this would have happened so the US
its influence and its its image is
declining its power is not declining its
power may actually be increasing okay so
I completely disagree with this claim
that the US is a declining power it may
actually be a power that's in that's
getting stronger and with the Advent of
AI it may become invincible who knows
all right so we have to look at the
world realistically not the I mean if
you if if somebody makes a claim that so
and so is happening you need be you need
to be able to properly fact check that
based on genuine hard information and
evidence and
data okay next question okay it's not a
question it's a statement shama
says the Ned the National Endowment for
what
democracy the National Endowment for
democracy is a proxy for the CIA they
were funding the student
protesters well the students were
protesting for democracy right so
obviously the Ned must fund them the Ned
has funded such student protests in
Thailand and other places also and they
may also be involved in India so what is
the Ned let's let's let's find out what
this Ned thing
is um
ah this is the Ned website n.org
okay the National Endowment for
democracy the Ned is a private nonprofit
Foundation dedic dedicated to the growth
and strengthening of democratic
institutions around the
world each year the NAD makes more than
2,000 grants to support the projects of
NOS abroad who are working for
Democratic goals in more than 200 more
than 100 countries so the us through the
NAD is interfering in the internal
matters clearly of more than 100
countries through NOS these noos are
supported by the Ned and various other
us
organizations yeah they're talking about
Russia blah blah blah blah blah blah and
so on so forth now and and see here look
interested in working at n see all the
job offerings dear Indians you want to
betray your country please go ahead and
and take up a job job at the Ned and I
promise you there are lots of Indians
who are working in somewhere or the
other in these organizations now let's
see what Wikipedia has to say about the
Ned now when it comes to Wikipedia it's
extremely biased when it comes to India
anti-india bias over here it could be
actually more reliable when it comes to
this thing the Ned now let's look at
this box here founded in November 1983
the founder is Carl gersman
and Alan
Weinstein interesting okay two
Americans okay it's a nonprofit NGO
location Washington
DC its Origins are the US Congress
resolution hr2 915 it serves in a
worldwide area outside the
US and so
on promoting political and Economic
Institutions such as political groups
trade unions political groups political
party ities within within countries
trade unions free markets business
groups what about
students upon its founding the NAD
assumed some former activities of the
CIA so down that's that's so transparent
now uh political groups activists
academics and some governments have said
that the Ned has been an instrument of
US foreign policy helping to Foster
regime change what happened in
Bangladesh was regime regime change so I
think what shiama is saying over here
makes an emminent amount of
sense and they may have be okay they may
may they have they may have been behind
the protest in Thailand let's put that
back on the screen Thailand and Malaysia
2020 th protests student protests Pro
government group cited Ned support for
protester sympathizing groups to assert
that the US government was masterminding
the
protests
Malaysia what about Bangladesh no
there's no mention of Bangladesh here
maybe it's it's it's too new so the Ned
is one of the
instruments through which the US helps
carry out regime change operations
coups which are then masked under the
Garb of student protests because
students are genu generally innocent
idealistic people who are very easy to
control but when students protest it
looks like it's some genuine cause right
so that is the The Playbook by which the
Americans conduct regime change and
that's what happened in Bangladesh and
they also used this to threaten Nations
and to coer them into complying with
various demands so you take a nation
like Thailand maybe the Americans wanted
the Tha government to do something and
maybe the th government did not want to
do that so what do you do you unleash
student protest for a couple of years
then eventually by through this arm
twisting the Tha government will back
down and do whatever they are told to do
that's how you do it so
that is the
Ned next
question Sun Moon 0877 says why are some
politicians in India making claims that
it could be Chinese money playing Behind
the B Bangladesh protests in the regime
change in Bangladesh it's not just some
politicians in India it is some very
prominent thinkers and analysts and
geopolitical experts on YouTube at Etc
who are saying that it could be Pakistan
and China behind
this yeah why are they doing this so I
can think of two or three reasons why we
would make that first of all you have to
be clueless to do that you have to be an
an expert with zero understanding of
geopolitics and the cause of cause and
effect came okay so I made this
prediction in November last year that
the us is going to carry out regime
change in Bangladesh I did not say it
would have it could be China or Pakistan
because in that video that I have put
out I have clearly laid out the pattern
of so-called
coincidences okay that typically goes in
the direction of a regime change
operation which has the Fingerprints of
the us all over it it has no
Fingerprints of Pakistan or China I mean
even the the the UK's High Commissioner
or Ambassador whatever was was meeting
with opposition leaders in a very
specific Manner and very specific people
in specific locations at the Beast of
the US so it was clear the signs and
symptoms and fingerprints were clear in
November last year itself to me that's
why I put out that
video so there is you know I know that
China is not a friend of indiaia
obviously it's an adversary Nation they
wanted they have wanted India to break
up for the P for the longest time since
the
1950s and they claim our land they've
tried to interfere all across the
subcontinent and and prop up governments
that are anti- India so yes that is true
they have done that in Maldives you have
a pro China government the nepales
political parties most of them are
pro-china which is not the Chinese fault
it is our fault so there are many
governments in the Indian subcontinent
that are you could say Pro China or
they've been set up with Chinese
assistance but in the case of Bangladesh
there is clear evidence of us
fingerprints all over the place so one
of the reason why politicians or who
whoever is making these claims one of
the reasons for that could be they are
clueless they have no understanding but
they need to make their voice
heard and most Indian the public is also
clueless so if you are a prominent
geopolitical
YouTuber
then people will believe you no matter
what you say there is one
cluelessness
secondly maybe some people are being
paid some okay some people may be paid
to make such statements so let me give
you an example okay I'm giving you an
example of a non-indian
person so there is this lady American
lady okay her name is cleop Pascal and
she generally is a has a very good takes
on geopolitics now let's go to her
Twitter her
ex cleop Pascal let see what she is
talking
about uh she
generally gives the appearance of being
very kind of pro-india
okay
uh okay this is not coming out
chronologically because I am operating
out of a different kind of
uh thing I haven't logged in but uh let
me see cleop Pascal's tweets and bring
up a pertinent tweet from
her okay let's put this on the
screen give me a second my friends I'm
putting it up so over here cleop Pascal
speaks about the ongoing Hindu genocide
anti-hindu programs in Bangladesh as we
speak there are horrible uh killings of
Hindus going on in a systematic manner
in Bangladesh so speaks she's speaking
about that horrific targeted attacks
Hindus going on in Bangladesh now and
this tweet is from August 7 two days ago
these are no longer student protests
something else is going on likely at
least Pakistan and PRC approval if not
complicity now this lady is
American so she is
being you could say loyal to a country
but she's also raising the the the issue
of what's happening in Bangladesh
against Hindus so she is claiming that
most like at least Pakistan and China
are behind this
okay so she's not paid to say that she's
an American so she will not talk about
our country but I think even Pakistani
analysts are now saying that the
Americans are behind this everybody is
clear about that so either the people
who are making claims about China being
involved in this they're either
completely clueless and they're idiots
or they or they have some kind of agenda
either they are being paid to do this or
they have some kind of loyalty towards
certain countries
because it is clearly not China that's
behind what's happened it is it has the
Fingerprints of the us all over
it okay two questions consum prin Singh
hello sir and Akash ja India is trying
its best to deter the Bangladesh's from
entering India but why no such
commitment in the case of
Manipur soon Uncle Sam will cut off cut
the India's Northeast off with a new
country and will be just watching it and
so they will continue to divide this
nation further so who those who left
this country and migrated to the US into
the Western countries were the right is
there no future for this country okay
both these questions are kind of
interrelated it's about India's Far East
it's about Manipur it's about what's
happening in Bangladesh all of this is
interrelated and I have spoken about
this before I've spoken about project K
project Cookie Land This is a pet
project of the Americans they want to
and sh see I am not making this claim
the former prime minister of Bangladesh
re spoke about this multiple times that
the Americans want to create an
artificial Christian Nation out of parts
of Bangladesh parts of Burma and parts
of
India and that is cooki Land Cookie Land
for Christ and in the
past several years maybe a decade past
decade or so hundreds of thousands of
illegal cookie infiltrators have
infiltrated into Manipur and many of
them VI mizoram why mizoram but into
Manipur hundreds of thousands in the
past few years and they've settled down
mostly in southern Manipur and about
half of Manipur is kind of Def facto
cookie territory and there is very
little influence of the government of
India there chura chanur is an
example does does Indian law really
apply in chura chanur
doubtful so that's the kind of situation
right now after this coup happened in
adesh this past week uh the Indian uh
paramilitary forces BSF Etc have been
put on high alert the border between
India and Bangladesh is kind of tightly
sealed there is nighttime curfew in
various places where the Border along
the border and so on so India is doing
it its best to prevent bangladeshis from
escaping from the violence and entering
India most of them who will want to
enter India will be Hindus and obviously
some other elements will try to enter
India while bem is going on so maybe
maybe it's about you know India of
course India doesn't care about Hindus
we know that India is the world's most
Hindu phobic Nation so if the
Bangladeshi Hindus die it's their
problem essentially that's how the
government of India thinks I don't think
that way I don't think M though but
maybe the government of India think that
so they are not our people they are
citizens of a foreign country M though
maybe the government of India thinks
that way and of course there are real
security threats because others could
also infiltrate into India IND uh while
while this is happening so India is
doing its best right now as Prince says
to deter Bangladesh from Bangladesh is
from entering India why no such
commitment in the case of Manipur I'll
tell you why there is there is this
disparity I'll tell you why let's go to
the map we haven't seen the map today
it's nearly one hour so the Far East of
India is where this all this activity is
happening we have Bangladesh which is
the which is former east east Bal and
currently East Pakistan and then we have
Myanmar and we have Manipur so when it
comes to Bangladesh it used to be East
Pakistan so India had very robust border
security infrastructure in place since
the
1950s okay and we have a very very
significant paramilitary and Military
presence all across the all along the
India East Pakistan border so because it
used to be East Pakistan in the past and
now it is again become is Pakistan
that's why we have a very robust border
infrastructure in the area and people
who don't remember people who are young
may not remember this they may not be
aware when Mr vajpai was in power there
was this border clash between India and
Bangladesh and the Bangladesh rifles
killed about between 10 to 20 Indian BSF
soldiers and India did nothing about it
so there's been a need for this robust
border military or paramilitary
infrastructure between India and
Bangladesh in the at the border that's
why India is able to clamp down if it
needs or if it wants on illegal
Bangladeshi in infiltration into India
if it wants of course we know that in
the past God knows how many years
Millions tens of millions of Bangladesh
has have crossed over illegally into
India in 2014 in 2014 the the figure
that was being given out by various
Indian government officials was 50
million bangladeshis illegally residing
in India in
2014 that's 10 years ago so today in
2024 the number may be close to 100
million so they have been allowed to
infiltrate into
India how did that happen what was done
in the past 10 years I don't want to ask
those questions right now so India has
the ability to prevent Bangladesh is
from entering India if India so desires
because of the very robust
border military and paramilitary
infrastructure now when it comes to
Manipur Manipur if you look at the
satellite
image and Burma there is no fencing on
the border There is almost no military
or paramilitary infrastructure along the
border the border is entirely open in
lots of places there is no demarcation
of the
Border okay and that's why it's
impossible for India even if it wants to
prevent cookies from entering Manipur
because India has never in invested in
Border infrastructure in the past 70 80
years in this
region and we have some paramilitary
presence in Manipur Assam rifles
but but you know what the less we speak
about the Assam rifles the better okay I
will not comment further than that so
that's
why it is impossible for India to
prevent next to impossible for India or
very difficult for India to prevent
cookies from Crossing into Manipur into
India when it comes to me to mizoram the
state south of Manipur I wonder how much
Indian military or paramilitary presence
even exists in this state and don't
blame Mr Modi blame the Miso
Accord and who was behind the Miso
Accord if if you want to find out do
some research and find out all the
information is out there in the public
domain who was the architect of the the
Miso Accord who was
that so because India has not invested
in infrastructure border infrastructure
in this region that's why even if India
wants it cannot stop cookies or it is
very hard for India to stop cookies from
entering Manipur right and uh yes the
past 10 years hundreds of thousands of
cookies came into India and settled
down and what was the government of
India doing I wonder clearly it is not
simply an intelligence failure it is a
strategic failure because it looks like
every single Indian government simply
doesn't understand this region the Far
East they have some advisers apparently
okay some some wonderful genius level
advisers who have never lived there who
have no understanding of the region
maybe they have been there once or twice
and they've read some books and they've
read some research papers and that's how
they become experts in this place and
then they advise the central government
about what should be the policies in the
region
and I will not venture to name any of
these advisers but those advisers are at
least to be partially held responsible
for what's happened since so the cookie
mediated violence did not start it
started officially in May 23 but the
ingredients for that were being put into
place long
before and this is not a Law and Order
issue this is a geopolitical issue and
that's why the Indian government should
have been alert to what's happening but
clearly they were dozing clearly they
were speak sleeping so and and the
ingredients for This Disaster well they
started being put into place in the 19th
century but it accelerated in the past
years and most of the blame goes to the
previous governments in Manipur not the
current beaning government who he
whatever criticisms you have about
beaning in his government at least he
tried to do some things right you know
the nighttime curfew ended in Manipur
ASA was REM removed from many various
parts of Manipur afpa have been in place
in Manipur in parts of this region since
1958 Armed Forces special power act can
you imagine living in such conditions so
the government the BJP Government tried
some things right but at a central level
there was a massive failure strategic
failure intelligence failure whatever
you want to call it and that's where we
are today but even if they wanted they
could have not stopped the cookies from
infiltrating because there is no border
infrastructure that can stop
them so that's where we are now this
this this can still be solved this
problem Manipur can still be made
terrorist free infiltrator free the
natives can again regain their their
territory of Manipur but it'll take
minimum 20 years there is no short-term
solution and a long-term solution will
involve 10 is beyond
India so there you have
it uh so next question
is is there no future for this country
there is a future for this country even
in the dest of stats there is there are
there is a possibility of a good future
but you will need a more sensible
approach to the region you will need the
government to consult people who
actually understand the region not
idiots who are
clueless then you will need a long-term
approach a long-term approach which
begin Begins
by
look what happens in the territory of
Burma what happens in the territory of
Bangladesh is technically and officially
Beyond India's control but what the
government of India can do is start
doing things in the territory that is
within your
jurisdiction there are foreign agents
running rampant in Indian Territory
there are foreign
agents who are controlling Indian
Territory or controlling
politics in Indian Territory one of the
major political players in the Far East
of India so-called Northeast is the
church it is what it is it is the church
that controls much of nagaland mizoram
and all the
cookies and there's much more happening
at least try to regain full sovereignty
in this region India government of India
what are you guys
doing so there's a lot that needs to be
done
you start now you can regain full
control not just in Manipur mizoram Etc
but in the entire region it's possible
it'll take 15 20 years but I would like
to see something start
now right
now I don't know that's what I'll
say Okay Anand vij sing says for the
security of India first get rid of the
western M missionary NOS seal the Border
against them yes yeah yeah Anand you're
right you're right you clearly are from
Sri Lanka but you know how it is in Sri
Lanka as well what they've done to your
people into your country right um and
that's what they have done across India
as well especially in the Far East of
India so yeah I know exactly what you
mean and the problem is that sealing the
Border won't do it because they are
within
India for decades they have been
receiving
Millions hundreds of millions of dollars
every year billions of dollars every
year and see what they're doing in
Punjab it is sixs who are being
converted to Christianity in in on an
industrial
scale the sick people the proud sick
people are now becoming Bible toting
zealots where's the where's where's the
self-respect what happened there is that
going on in the Far East the whole place
has been devastated the indigenous cult
has been stamped
out so the first thing that needs to
happen look I have nothing against
you if you are a Christian my dear
viewer in case any of you are Christians
I have nothing against you being a
Christian you should follow your heart
if your heart says Jesus is Lord then
you please follow Jesus Christ I have
nothing against any individual following
their individual
path okay absolutely nothing whatever
religion you think is best for you
please follow it it need not be an
Indian indigenous religion whatever it's
an individual
Choice my problem is when religion is
being used to artificially re-engineer
demographics in India so as to so as to
make that
region uh develop extra National
allegiances and that is something that's
happened all over the world the
Europeans and the westerners are Past
Masters at this so I am not specifically
targeting this religion or that religion
or X religion or Y
religion I have a problem with religion
being used as the pretext to re-engineer
demographics and and uh create US extr
Territorial loyalties extra National
loyalties in populations within my
nation and the church is known to do
that no question about it the Russ the
the the the Chinese wrote about this in
the 19th century the Japanese have been
writing about this the past several
centuries everyone knows this so yes the
government of India needs to how long
will you just bend the knee and pretend
like nothing's happening you got to do
something people should be allowed
should people have the fundamental right
to practice any religion they want but
religion should not be militarized and
politicized and they should not be
certain religious organizations with
funding from abroad should not try to
interfere in the internal activities of
internal matters of a Nation through
religion so that's why I agree with what
Anand says shut down the foreign funding
of of various missionary uh
organizations Etc wherever they are
within India and if they are and
investigate their activities because
they are known to act as conduits for
foreign influence in the
country har Agarwal says should India
invade and take over the northern part
of Bangladesh to widen the chicken's
neck neck as well as the chatram area
and for tripura to get C SE access if
the situation worsens just like 71 we
should have done this in 1971 I believe
uh H I agree with you that we should
have done this in 1971 what is herel
talking about let's let's go to the map
and see so we're talking about the
chicken snck area which is the Siliguri
Corridor this here town is Siliguri it's
in West Bengal I don't know why West
Bengal extends all the way here but
whatever okay so it's it's part of West
Bengal it is mainly inhabited by
Bangladeshi infiltrators today
Siliguri and this is a very vulnerable
area it's about 50 kilometers wide
roughly let me see measure distance the
the 26 kilometers very thin strip of
land if a foreign if if a foreign
adversary you know occupies the small
area of land it will cut off India's
access to between the Far East and the
mainland so-call Mainland so it's an
extremely strategically vulnerable area
region piece of land for India and in 71
India should ideally have absorbed the
whole of reabsorbed the whole of
Bangladesh into India or at least
widened this this access point this this
area so we didn't do it in 71 huge lost
opportunity once again chram the chagang
hill tracks this was a majority Buddhist
area majority Hindu Buddhist area today
I think Buddhist and Hindus naturally
are in a minority here now and there is
this tremendous oppression that's
happening for decades over here so this
area also should have been taken over by
India in 71 I don't understand why sth
was ever made part of East Pakistan s
should have been part of India Raj Shai
also and so on so it should have been
done in 71 now what if India does this
today if India does this today we will
immediately face sanctions from the
United States who will seek to devastate
India's economy
so uh I would say that s that that it is
very dangerous for India to do such a
thing because the Americans will impose
horrible sanctions on India and we are
not Russia we are not an otari and they
will try to devastate destroy India
completely uh but maybe you should
sometimes take a risk I don't know if
India's government can ever
be you know can ever be capable of
taking risks but you know these are the
various regions of Bangladesh and
rangpur rajshahi kulna should ideally be
reabsorbed or they should be made Indian
protectorates maybe a Hindu region in
Bangladesh where the Hindus can live
safely sth should be part of India again
and Chong should be part of India or
maybe once again kept as a
protectorate uh that is under India's
protection ideally that should happen
but I think it's too early for that to
happen and maybe India is not strong
enough not powerful enough to do that
and maybe the government of India is too
risk ours for that and maybe they are
right in being risk ours when it comes
to this matter so I think look if you
look at the Indian subcontinent in the
balance of power India is clearly the
most powerful Nation
but that is not sufficient because in
the subcontinent despite India being the
way most powerful Nation you all the
other nations are proxies of more
powerful Nations Pakistan is a proxy of
the US Nepal is sadly to some extent a
proxy of China the Maldives are a proxy
of China Sri Lanka is a failed proxy of
the US and China then Bangladesh is now
a newly minted US vasal state and
Myanmar is a nation that's torn by a us
imposed Civil War so if you mess with
Bangladesh the Americans will get
involved if you mess with Pakistan the
Americans will get involved if you mess
with Nepal the Chinese may want to get
involved and so on so forth so that's
the situation despite India being the
overwhelmingly most powerful Nation here
all other nations are proxies of more
powerful Nations and that's what is the
problem right now so India needs to be
patient how long will we be patient Etc
should we just go ahead and take a risk
well I
think well I'm not the guy in Power so
don't ask me ask Mr
Modi AUA says I want to help the
Pakistani and Bangladeshi persecuted
Hindus what can a common man do about
this so right now there is this genocide
essentially a genocide or at least
pogram that's happening against the
Hindus in Bangladesh I have seen things
that I would never want to see again on
on social media and and people from
various parts sending me stuff I
never things that I I never wish anybody
has to see so there is a fullscale
genocide happening against the
Bangladesh Hindus
and and in Pakistan we know how the
situation is Right Dire
Straits so the current the powers that
be in Bangladesh the ones who have taken
power they want to reduce the Hindu of
Bangladesh to the level of Pakistan the
level in Pakistan maybe about 2% right
now what's the Hindu population of
Pakistan 2% 1% roughly maybe 3% I'm not
sure probably less than 3% in Bangladesh
it's in in 71 it was
22% in about 50 years today 24 in 2024
the population of Hindus is about 7%
7.5% in Bangladesh and they want to make
it less than less than 2% in a few years
so the Americans want the Bangladesh is
to finish what they had started in 71
and India stopped them from from doing
that the
Bangladeshi the East Pakistan government
was conducting a genocide of Hindus in
71 the Americans knew it very well and
they wanted this to happen in India
stopped it so today's US Government
wants this to resume and it should be
taken to the logical conclusion so
Bangladesh need they from the American
perspective they want Bangladesh to
become a fully Islamic State just like
Pakistan they want Bangladesh to to
become East Pakistan again because that
is when it will fully serve the US
properly as a counterweight to India so
India has counterweights on both both
sides now east and west and then you
will have kilan also so that that's what
they wish for India to completely
encircle India and cut off India from
various parts of the world now the point
is what can Indians do what can the
common man woman in India do about the
genocide of of Hindus in Bangladesh
nothing except for spr
awareness there is nothing you can do
that can affect what's that can affect
or change what's happening on the ground
right now unfortunately as you speak in
Bangladesh but what you can do is raise
awareness you everybody has social media
accounts you have Facebook Twitter X
Instagram whatever do it judiciously but
spread
awareness keep doing that every day
that's the best you can do so how long
can the world ignore
this so if we Indians 1.4 billion of us
at least at least a billion of us we
can't expect all 1.4 billion of of us to
be involved in this or support this but
whatever at least a billion of us can do
it spread awareness daily so hopefully
that makes some
difference okay Cal danal says what
happened to me today after listening to
each and every word of my previous live
stream the emergency
episode is that my innocence shattered
big time I'm so sorry and now all I'm
doing is
crying yeah I am sorry if I had my my
episode had that effect on
you uh yesterday I I I recorded a
podcast on another
channel uh I'll not name the the person
it'll come out soon so that guy good
friend of mine
we we discussed this okay he hosted me
on his podcast we recorded that
yesterday and after I I went into the
whole details of the matter the
Bangladesh issue and how it has happened
who's behind this what are India's
options what are the options of the
people who live in Bangladesh after I
went into great detail about all of that
at the end he said that his inoc
innocence has been shattered and what
black pill or something something like
that so yeah unfortunately that is the
truth can be sometimes extremely
hard to
take but it is better to know what's
really happening in the world than to be
ignorant and think everything is good
while everything's burning around
you uh so you can't be innocent forever
innocent essentially comes from
innocence often comes from ignorance
essentially and and ignorance isn't good
we want most people in India to not be
ignorant they should know what's
genuinely really happen happening in the
world in India in our in our
neighborhood we know need to know what's
really happening ignorance will take us
to to
disaster if you don't know what's
happening then you think everything is
fine and hunky dory and at the end of
the day one fine day it's your
turn so I am sorry that uh that the that
confronting the truths made you cry and
all but uh and I I am not that
pessimistic it's not in we not in a
situation
that we are
reasonably safe we are reasonably
reasonably powerful we are like a middle
power we have enemies all around us but
so what but so what we are 1.4 billion
billion of us we have reasonably good
leadership right now yes we would love
to have another leader like shivaji
Maharaj or somebody of the caliber of
the cholas rajendra Chola or or or Kumar
Gupta or or his son scand Gupta
or kanishka or Ashok Chand Ashok we need
some of the chess right
now maybe the person already exists so I
think we should be more optimistic I
know things aren't great things have
never been completely fine okay and uh
if you have problems in life it means
you have opportunities also to do
something good so see it in a positive
light I know things aren't great but
things have never been great fully great
the past 10,000 years tell me when was
the last time things were great for
India so it's not it's nothing new it's
nothing new in 62 when Mr Neu the great
magnificent Mr Neu was ruling the
country where things great for India no
we lost territory we we were defeated by
China so we have seen worse days we have
seen the invasions of Gori gnavi nadara
we have seen much worse days and we have
come out of that and we are here right
now and at least right now we are in
nuclear power and there's a lot that's
going on that's going well for us and if
the world's biggest power the superow
does something in our neighborhood it's
not something that we should cry
about it's okay we'll we'll get through
this so my main uh message is don't be
pessimistic I know it is kind of
unnerving and and and painful to come
face to face with the unwarned ugly
truth of the world but you get used to
it and don't be pessimistic India India
will do very well long
term next question is by Arnav is a coup
possible in India and can a country be
really cou
free is a coup possible in India look a
military coup is very unlikely in India
India is that sort of a Nation so so
large so multi multil linguist
multilingual so multi kind of snake Etc
it's impossible for a coup a military
coup to succeed in India it's
essentially
impossible next time I'll get my book
the book by Dr Edward lutwak in which he
puts out the preconditions for a coup to
succeed in any Nation one of the
conditions is that the nation should be
single ethnicity secondly there should
be only one political Center of power
not multiple centers of power and so on
so forth there are so many conditions
that India simply doesn't satisfy so a
military coup is not possible in India
but what about another kind of coup
what
about if it's not a military coup but a
different kind of takeover all your
educational institutions are taken over
silently by a foreign ideology or a
foreign country or a foreign ideology or
a group of individuals who espouse a
certain ideology and they are supported
by a foreign country the entire
education system is taken over the uh
media is taken over in the same way the
entertainment industry is taken over in
the same way and then all the various
government in institutions are also
compromised in the same way so over a
period of 20 30 years the entire nation
gets completely compromised all the
institutions are infiltrated at from
bottom to top by agents of a foreign
country and
then even the
leader and and also further further
beyond that what are what if some
political parties are also infiltrated
and taken over by foreign countries they
come under come they become part of the
foreign they they they get put on a
foreign
payroll okay so you have the education
system you have the media you have the
entertainment industry you have a
variety of political parties you have
various National
institutions what if all of this is
taken over infiltrated from top to
bottom by by agents of a foreign country
then eventually you will have eventually
in this hypothetical scenario in the
future you may have Chief
ministers in various States okay
hypothetically who have an allegiance to
a foreign country and eventually you may
have a prime minister in this
hypothetical future scenario who
hypothetically has allegiance to a
foreign country in that so in this
scenario it takes time it takes time 20
30 40 50 years but eventually you're
gone you finished and this is a complete
takeover irreversible
takeover
irreversible so if you have if the
foreign power is patient enough they can
do it so quietly so insidiously so
silently and so all pervasively that the
people will never even know what
happened to
them so that is possible in India and
some people would would allegedly say
that something like this is allegedly
perhaps in the
works so can you see the signs and
symptoms of
that if you can and if it is true then
look out for
it enemy translation 1030 says any
chance of anything like the Bangladesh
coup happening in India in the future
also what according to you is The Stance
or Moral Moral stance of the Indian
military with regards to Modi and with
regards to Hindus I know military rule
is absolutely never an option but still
if that happens would it be safe for
Indian Hindus so like I said in the
previous
answer uh a cool like Bangladesh will
probably not happen in India but India
can certainly be taken over insidiously
slowly silently over a number of years
or decades by compromising all the infil
all the institutions and infiltrating
all the institutions top to bottom that
can happen but it takes a lot of time
for that to happen but we may be at some
stage in the process allegedly
okay uh so that's answer that's the
answer to the first part of the
question what is the stance of the
Indian military with regards to Modi and
with regards to Hindus the Indian
military is a genuinely completely
secular
institution they uh don't discriminate
on the basis of religion they don't they
don't consider religion at
all uh so the the military is genuinely
secular and uh
they uh they have complete allegiance to
the nation of India and to the command
and control structure and at the top of
the command and control structure you
have the prime minister of
India or the president technically but
it's actually the Prime Minister okay
the president is just a decorative uh
figurehead in the country so when it
comes to the military they will
always do the right thing and take
orders without question from the topmost
political leadership in India from the
Prime Minister and there is no question
of of of uh that not
happening now what is the stance of the
Indian military towards Hindus see most
of the Indian military are
Hindus okay and they may have this
secular ethos and all that but the at
the end of the day they are
Hindus most of them and there are
various regiments that have these war
cries for the G regiment it is Kiki Soo
laglo for the rajput regiment every
regiment has a specific war cry that is
either ethnic or
religious and many of these war cries
are Hindu war
cries um so overall there is nothing
that India would need to fear from the
Indian military ever no question the
question doesn't Arise at all uh now the
last part of the question is military
rule is absolutely never an option but
still if that happens would India would
it be safe for Indian
Hindus so let's entertain this
hypothetical scenario completely
hypothetical scenario in which there is
military rule rule in India would that
be safe for
Hindus this hypothetical scenario in
which there is military rule in India in
this hypothetical
scenario it will be much safer for
Hindus than what we have
today because the military is genuinely
secular and they will not they will
treat everybody equ
y okay and they will not discriminate on
the basis of religion whoever you are
whatever your religion is so today the
situation in in in Modern India is that
there is discrimination on the basis of
religion and Hindus are at the bottom of
the pile India is the most hinduphobic
Nation if you look at India's
Constitution or if you look at India's
laws or India's policies or whatever
Hindus are the third class citizens in
India and Hindus always get the short
end of the stck stick in
everything
so if there is military rule in India
that actually things will be much better
for Hindus and for
everybody then if you look back at past
history okay there's been no military
rule since 47 before 47 you had foreign
military rule which is British rule
before that you had turkic rule the the
Turks in between there was marata which
which was great for India the maratas
were great but if you look at the
greatest
rulers of
India whether it is if you go back to
and a half thousand years Ashok the
great before that Chandra Gupta Maia
then you
had um keska the great then you had the
Gupta
Emperors Chandra Gupta kumara Gupta
skandagupta
samudra Gupta and so on then you had if
you look at the greatest rulers of India
they were all essentially military
rulers you know that
so it's not like military rule is always
bad uh so I would say that look if in
this
completely impossible hypothetical
scenario when the if if the Indian
military actually ends up ruling India
it would actually be safer for Hindus
and the policies will be genuinely
egalitarian and genuinely secular unlike
today unlike
today okay San says San Panda says what
camp is Pakistan in now with recent
developments such as the Bangladesh
coup maybe Pro
pakistan11 million dollar funds from the
US and Trump assassination attempt by
Pakistani it seems Pro us or deep state
but in the other hand there are rumors
that Pakistan will supply missiles to
Iran which seems pro-china so which Camp
is Pakistan in is it playing all the
players okay so the good question
Pakistan so you may remember a couple of
years ago there was a coup in Pakistan
it did not look like a coup but Imran
Khan the elected prime minister was
removed from government shortly after he
had this distinct Misfortune of visiting
Putin meeting Putin on the day that
Putin launched his special military
operation in Ukraine so it was
exceptionally bad luck and bad timing
but Iman Khan was removed from power it
was a coup and whoever came next was
placed in power so that was the end of
the Imran Khan experiment and Imran Khan
was strongly pro-china he was becoming
too pro pro China for anyone's liking in
the US so he was removed and a new
government comes in power and that's a
pro US Government so Pakistan is in the
US Camp they do they still call China
their iron brother and all that but they
are in the US Camp I don't know about
the Trump assassination attempt by
Pakistani I'm not aware of that but yeah
you talking about rumors that Pakistan
will supply missiles to Iran and that
would seem Pro China because Iran is pro
China so is Russia there there is you
know this talk of this access right
China Russia Iran North Korea that sort
of access so if pakist so what has
Pakistan said Pakistan said that if
there is a war between Israel and Iran
then Pakistan will supply arms to Iran
that's what Pakistan has said So when
you say something it is words blah blah
blah blah
blah okay I can say anything I want but
it doesn't mean I'll do that do you
understand because if Pakistan supplies
arms to Iran in a war against Israel it
will be going up against America's
number one Ally Israel and I promise you
this will never
happen it won't happen they are doing
this just to keep the public on their
side but they will never ever actually
do
that so words are different from actions
people can make a million promises they
don't have to keep any of those okay
there are lots of uh lots of ways of of
wriggling out of a promise so
uh so Pakistan is pro us Pakistan is in
the US Camp Pakistan is a US client
State Pakistan is a US wasal state as
long as the US needs Pakistan Pakistan
won break up Pakistan won't
disintegrate and the US needs Pakistan
then the US needs Pakistan as a cbate to
India
so Pakistan is in the US Camp Pakistan
is a US puppet us
vasal Shan 97 says reports saying
reports are saying that the US
transferred $293 million to the to the
Taliban accidentally well obviously in
the real world in geopolitics there are
no accidents seems like Uncle Sam is
cooking some something against
good question now first of all where is
Afghanistan on the map so Afghanistan
isn't doesn't have currently a common
border with India because gilg balistan
Etc and and PO is current currently
temporarily under Pakistani occupation
so Afghanistan India don't have
currently a common border so if the
Americans are transferring let's say
some money to the
Taliban it'll be hard for the Taliban to
use use it against India because they
are on bad terms with Pakistan etc etc
etc the Taliban actually are on
reasonably good terms with India and
their number one enemy is Pakistan so
just like the Americans use Pakistan as
a counterweight to India the same way
they use the Taliban which rules
Afghanistan is a counterweight to
Pakistan so that Pakistan also
behaves it is alleged that the US gives
a stipend of
between 40 to 80 million per week in
cash
to the
Taliban now let's take a look at that
allegation shall we so one of the people
who has been saying this consistently is
the former vice president of of
Afghanistan Amah
s so this is a tweet by him in October
2022 the so-called humanitarian $40
million per week is delivered in
coordination with a group in a
sentimentally politically and ethnically
divided Afghanistan it is therefore
inevitable for Talib to use it for their
own consider ation the living and dead
Talib are the priority recipients there
is no
oversight so here he is being kind of
indirect let's see a next tweet from
2023 January 1 on January 3 and 4 the
Talib are going to receive 80 million US
Dollars consolidation funds in the name
of humanitarian Aid this is just less
than a week after women were erased from
all types of work and education cash
will be flown by flight number so and so
hypocritical conduct next tweet March 8
2023 us 80 million from us and EU was
delivered to the Taliban this week alone
today is March 8 International women's
day with zero oversight there is no
doubt that the cash will help the Talib
consolidate and do more of what they do
including further repression of women
next tweet uh April 23 un appeasement
strategy of justifying us $40 million
cash delivery to the to the Taliban per
week didn't work in absence of
legitimate government Nos and
independent oversight any so-called Aid
will directly help the Taliban Jun hun
to consolidate women's staff of un are
erased from work and the UN is
retreating a tweet from June 2023 the
effort by the supporters of the in
Infamous Doha deal to stabilize the
Taliban 2.0 by providing 40260 million
us per week in the name of humanitarian
assistance is going nowhere uh the Bold
aspect of Taliban rule is anti-human
international the paid media media is
failing to magnify their non-existing
goodness
too portraying the Talib said good thing
as is like selling fish from a septic
tank and this is an interesting tweet
from July 4 2023 did Washington continue
to give $60 million or its equivalent
per week to the Viet Kong after the US
withdrew from Vietnam did Somalia
receive any funding from the us a week
after the US withdrawal and Blackhawk
incident did they the Doha deal
conspiracy has nothing to do with
humanitarian issues the money is passed
to help the Talib consolidate and use
the national revenue on military if
Talib are poor then why their
intelligence department is twice the
size of the Republic's
NDS and over here it's a long long tweet
about Antonio
Gutierrez uh so honorable Antonio
Gutierrez your is great however in
practice your unama news justifies
provision of $60 million a week to the
Taliban who have erased women from
Afghan life and Society the Talib have
turned the women into indoor slaves do
Afghan women exist in the UN map why are
the why do the Afghan people have no
access to information on how those Hefty
us60 billion are spent humanitarian
projects are supposed to be the most
transparent once and so on so forth long
long tweet the point is
if the US has transferred $293 million
to the Taliban it's not happened
accidentally they have been paying
between 40 to 60 to 80 million per week
for the longest time ever since the
Taliban took over power in Afghanistan
they did not take over power in
Afghanistan they did not conquer
Afghanistan they were handed the country
on a plate by the Americans the Taliban
are a US proxy so yes India has to be
careful India has to be extremely
careful but we have reasonably good
relations with the Taliban we have way
better relations with the Taliban than
we have with
Pakistan the Taliban are pashu
nationalists they also understand that
it is dangerous to take money from the
US but they are taking it for the
time are how
much to what extent are they under Us
control I would not say they are 100%
under under under Us control but they
there may be some tacit agreements part
of the DU deal and much of the Dua deal
is secret the text is secret so there is
some agreement some understanding there
will be some limits but to some extent
the Taliban are us agents so India
should be I'm sure India is very much
cognizant of
that okay this is by Anand VI sing
abijit don't worry a time will come when
India will be the greatest power on
Earth is a sinhala Buddhist Sri Lankan I
say that we Sri Lankans will stand right
beside our Indian relatives and Friends
in as in ancient times to help you
achieve that shrining goal as you say
India must continue along the path being
blazed by Mr Modi with the objective of
preserving the territorial Integrity of
India eradicating poverty and social
injustices within India strengthening
its Armed Forces educating and
leveraging the awesome intellect of the
Indi people to grow India's economy into
the richest nation in the world and to
lead the gr Global South towards a more
Equitable a better more Equitable world
the people of India have the intrinsic
brains sensible temperament and the
inherent ability to achieve that Jo
India Jo Sri Lanka Ananda thank you so
much for those very kind words uh we are
the same people India Sri Lanka we are
currently separate Nations but we are
part of the same civilization we have
the same ancestors the same past the
same shared culture the same shared
history and hopefully the same shared
future so thank you so much for your
kind words I know Sri Lanka is going
through a bit of a bad time but yes
India
historically has been the world's
largest economy
consistently forever essentially as long
as it it has existed so we have gone
through a bad time we together India
Lanka the whole subcontinent we have
gone through a bad time bad thousand
years it's not a very big amount of time
in the context of the larger history so
now we if we get things right the next
20 years our rise will again happen
properly and when India Rises I would
like India to rise all along with all
our all our ancient friends and
relatives in the subcontinent and Beyond
L Sri Lanka Burma uh Nepal Thailand
Indonesia everybody all of us who have
historically been part of this great
civilization Could Happen together uh we
may perhaps remain separate Nations but
it doesn't stop us from being the same
civilization so I hope there are much
better days ahead for all of us together
I know it's a long journey out there
it's going to be a difficult Journey but
I'm very optimistic I have like like you
I have full confidence in the inherent
abilities of our people so thank you so
much once
again Matas says hello from Brazil I
root for for India and I hope Brazil and
India become closer and increase their
partnership in the future I have a
question for your next ask abijit
episode do you think the relations and
cooperation between Brazil and India
will increase going for forward and how
can the two Nations best help each other
look a great question and and great to
hear from you thank you so much for
rooting for India we also root for
Brazil we we have a in India have a lot
of admiration for Brazil for a variety
of reasons
football Brazil is probably the best
football playing nation in the world
with this great sporting history and so
many other things lovely country
wonderful people lot of potential in bra
as well just like India uh so what can
so I we also root for Brazil I also
personally root for for Brazil one of my
favorite countries so what what can
India do how can the relationship go
forward in the future uh I hope the
relationship gets closer there are so
many avenues for potential future
cooperation the two Nations should
invest in each other's economies there
is a lot that Brazil has to offer to
India there's a lot that India has to
offer to Brazil we should find areas of
convergence of of require
convergence of Interest I think there's
a lot of convergence of
interests uh for
example why not have the aviation
company Embraer which produces such
wonderful aircraft set up production
lines in India India should invite them
to do that offer land offer whatever is
required and have Embraer produced
aircraft in India various kinds of
aircraft India already has bought a few
Embraer aircraft which serve as avax
aircraft advanced war warning radar
systems which fly in the air military
aircraft uh why not produce Embraer
aircraft for for India's domestic
Aviation sector that's just one example
I'm sure Brazil has so many other
Industries and and technological things
to to offer to the rest of the world
India needs all of that so we can work
together uh it is a win-win for Brazil
it's and India as well so that's just
one example I'm sure we can find so many
other examples in case the in case the
viewers don't know let me put this on
the screen Embraer a wonderful Brazilian
company produces wonderful
aircraft uh here we have
it
Embraer so it's a Brazilian
multinational uh Corporation they have
all kinds of aircraft some of these are
those you know the aircraft that
millionaires have uh private aircraft
but they also have passenger aircrafts
they also have military transport
aircraft for example let me see this
yeah there's some deal that could happen
between the Indian Air Force in Brazil
they have commercial aircraft no
passenger aircraft so Embraer is a
wonderful company why can't India and
Brazil work together Vis with respect to
Embraer and various other other
companies and various other
uh uh you know Fields where there is
Convergence of requirements and all that
that there's a lot I think we can
explore uh so yeah there's a lot we can
do and I hope there is increasing
cooperation going forward and I
definitely wish nothing but the best of
luck to the people of Brazil the
wonderful people of Brazil and the
wonderful nation of Brazil Brazil also
has a tremendous amount of potential
just like India and I would like to see
it do really
well okay
let's take a couple more questions
Priyanka says what is the US's motive in
coercing European nations to allow large
scale migration of illegal military age
men into their territories is it aimed
at creating total Anarchy in these
nations and their complete anation
through infighting among various
European nations what are My Views look
what yeah there is no doubt that the
European nations why are the EU
are being coerced into accepting a
tremendous tremendous
inflow continuing inflow of military age
men from certain parts of the world West
Asia and parts of Africa
essentially these are all young men
almost no women and children coming in
and then these men settle down and
impose their culture on the natives they
are generally quite violent quite
misogynistic
Etc and the police forces of the host
Nations do nothing to stop this but
clamp down on anybody any natives trying
to prevent this from happening and
that's why you see all this Anarchy
across Europe right now so clearly the
EU is forcing these European nations to
accept this illegal immigration and the
EU is controlled by the US so why is the
US doing that even the US has open has
op it has opened its Southern border the
Biden regime has forced the American
public American citizenry
to absorb millions of illegal immigrants
undocumented ille immigrants so what's
being done why is this happening it is
being done one what is the effect of
this the effect of this is the
annihilation is is the is the
annihilation of local culture local
ethnicity of indigenous culture and
ethnicity so if you are an in indigenous
let's say British person you're white
you're Anglo Saxon or you're your your
Celtic gallic Welsh
whatever you have an indigenous language
you have an indigenous religion and
culture well not really very indigenous
but past 1,000 years you've been
practicing Christianity so it's your
indigenous indigenous culture now and
these foreign infiltrators they come
they settle down they impose their
culture on your on you and eventually
they start dominating various cities
towns Villages and so on and eventually
there's going to be a cultural religious
ethnic takeover so what does that do
it's going to create essentially a
monoculture across Europe the same
culture eventually starts dominating
Europe right right now Europe is very
distinctively multiethnic and
multilingual
multilingual but eventually you will
have the same ethnicity and same
language and same religion across Europe
what does that enable the controlling
power to do it enables the culture
controlling power to establish a world
government it's a world takeover and
Europe is the easiest lwh hanging fruit
right now so eventually whoever is
behind this wants to establish a world
government and it starts with Europe it
starts with the west and they don't care
and it's also clear that they
have they don't care at all for the
native Western culture and ethnicity and
language that's also pretty apparent
interesting so that is why they're doing
it kushagra Kalashnikov says is there
any chance of a world government
becoming reality oh if so what would
follow will that be truly good for
society I just spoke about world
government is there a chance of this
happening in the next 50 to 100 years
there will be a single government in
Europe because Europe will by the time
become a not just Europe but the entire
West much of the West will probably
become a single ethnicity single
language single culture single religion
because of this Mass immigration that is
being
conducted so if that happens it's going
to be very bad for the people and a
single a world government is essentially
a dictatorship a tyan tyrannical
dictatorship so it could happen it could
happen un unless the native
people resist if the native people of
Europe and these various host countries
don't resist and they allow the
governments to trample rough sh over
their
their aspirations in in their culture
and their ethnicity then then this will
happen so they've got to resist but if a
world government does indeed happen it
will be a tyrannical dictatorship and
human then Humanity will be enslaved and
reduced to the level of of domestic
animals cows sheep Etc the
yaj Noka has a very long couple of
questions okay number one the majority
of South Korean men practice
circumcision as the majority of
Americans do unlike the North Koreans
dog meat is recently banned in in South
Korea unlike in North Korea where dog
mate is available in restaurants how can
a society like that of South Korea be so
completely westernized in just a few
decades when Hindus under British rule
did not westernize to that extent it's
because of the of the differing nature
of of the two societies Indian Society
is at least 10,000 years old we've had
the same culture same civilization for
at least 10,000 years years we are the
oldest known culture and civilization in
the world and because we have this
incredibly ancient tradition that is
essentially in our
blood that's why it was so difficult for
the British to to westernize us they
tried there trying since the middle of
the since the beginning of the 18th
century to westernize us to christianize
us all that they've been trying that but
we were incredibly resilient despite in
unbearable hardships despite genocide
despite Millions hundreds of millions of
us being starved to death despite
massacres and large scale genocide we
still were able to resist the South
Koreans don't have that deep of a
culture that they also have a history
that goes back 2,000 plus years but
clearly they were not that resilient so
in just a few short years under the US
occupation the South Koreans have become
either completely atheistic or majority
Christian by now and they idolize the
West they want to be whiter than the
whites they want to be gayer than the
gays I really like South Korean culture
the indigenous culture there's a lot of
Beauty in that but what's happening in
South Korea is a complete destruction of
an indigenous culture so we because of
our incredible Antiquity how ancient our
culture and civilization is that's why
we were able to resist the British but
today that process is still going on the
process the British started in the
beginning of the 18th century is still
going on and today it looks like Indian
culture will crumble today because of
Tik Tok no what Instagram reals and what
not Bollywood and and what in the
education system and the entertainment
industry now it looks like in a few
years Indian culture will disappear and
by the end of the 21st century probably
what you call Hinduism if we are not
careful it won't exist
anymore so that's the answer to the
first question second question is
Filipinos and whites intermar much more
than turkey origin Turks and whites do
in the west but turkey origin Turks and
whites are considered closer racially
than Filipinos and whites Caribbean
origin blacks in the west also intermar
with whites much more than whites in
Turkey Orin Turks intermar in the West
so in the case of intermarriage religion
trumps race do you agree most likely
yes
yeah yes Turks are much more likely to
to intermar with Turks than to intermar
with whites like Europeans westerners
right and so on so it probably is
because of culture probably is because
of culture and religion religion culture
sometimes are part of the same thing
sometimes they're part of two different
things and so on so
yeah yes I think I think there seems to
be significant uh data points that that
kind of would make me agree with what
you're saying in case of intermarriage
generally religion trumps
Race For example let's let's talk about
a few Indian origin
Americans Nikki Haley is of Indian
origin but okay Nikki Hal is of Indian
origin Bobby Jindal who people have
forgotten push Jindal Bobby Jindal he's
of Indian origin VI ramaswami is of
Indian
origin um Tuli gabard is not of Indian
origin she has 0% Indian
ethnicity now Tulsi is a Hindu Viv is a
Hindu Nikki is a converted Christian and
Bobby Jindal is a converted Christian so
from the perspective of most most
Indians we will find much more Affinity
with people like VI and Tuli
gabard even though Tuli gabard is 0%
Indian eth
ethnically compared to someone like
Nikki Haley or Bobby Jindal because
they've converted to a foreign religion
so I think overall in the case of
intermarriage and in the case of
cultural religious Affinity religion
definitely trumps race
definitely Sun Moon 0877 says is over
sexualization the cause of of the fall
fall of the Roman Empire is that what's
happening now in the western
Nations I
think over sexualization of or or what
what would be called sexual perversion
it's not the cause of the fall of an
Empire it's typically a symptom of the
decline of an Empire which will
eventually lead to the fall of an Empire
let me give you an example you mentioned
Rome let's go to Google and let me refer
you all to a somewhat less known Roman
Emperor his name was Ila
gabao also known as Helio gabal so this
gentleman was a Roman Empire
for about three or four years very
shortlived short railed short short
ruled
Emperor and let me just tell you that he
was a piece of work he was a real piece
of work this guy
okay
every what you would call sexual
perversion you can imagine this guy was
was very much fond of all of that so
this guy ruled at a time when the Roman
Empire was in Decline it was in Decay
and his rule was a symptom of the
decline and
Decay and decline in standards overall
of of Roman of the Roman Empire so
that's an example of that so this guy
was full of he life was was was a study
in sexual perversion okay so over
sexualization focusing on sex all the
time and focusing on Deviant sexuality
or whatever the hell all that stuff is
whatever it is these are symptoms of the
decline of an Empire or a culture it
doesn't directly cause the fall of an
Empire or a culture it is a symptom of
the decline an impending fall of a
culture so when culture or an Empire
reaches a very high level of prosperity
and they've essentially solved all the
problems and defeated all the enemies
then what do you do now is the question
see human life is meaningless without
struggle you don't have any big mountain
to climb or a big task to do then your
life feels mundane and
pointless that's why people who
face adversity generally live meaningful
life even if they may not succeed in the
end so the greatest stories you know the
greatest heroes are the ones who
overcame the greatest obstacles who face
the most
hardships the most um the story is that
you like the most of the ones of the
greatest struggle right and struggle is
generally pain so when you have as a
society as as an Empire no struggle no
problems to solve then you start looking
to create problems that you can
solve and creating problems that
typically leads to all these weird
manifestations of of behavior like what
you call over sexualization or some
people would call sexual perversion and
all that so it's a symptom of the
decline of an Empire it is not something
that will directly cause the fall of the
Empire but yeah when these things crop
up you can tell something is wrong in
that Empire in that culture and it if
they're not careful they're going to go
down the wrong path and eventually fall
so yes something like that is happening
in the West
the West the past 500 years they started
rising and conquering the world and they
eventually overran most of the world and
destroyed most of the Nations and now
you will see that Nations like Russia
China India are emerging as powers in
their own right Russia can't be
destroyed China is also grown to the
second largest economy status India is
the fourth or fifth largest economy soon
to be third largest
economy so in in the west what whatever
growth it it experienced in the past few
centuries was very rapid growth was not
because of their superiority of culture
or intellect it was because of their
superiority in
applying organized violence on others
and now they
can't so whatever plunder they had they
had accumulated which which allowed them
to build these these these beautiful
cities and and countries is now that
where do where does the wealth come from
they can't steal anymore
so they are facing this dilemma right
now and there is no real way
out um so yeah eventually the West will
fall sooner or
later if it unless it
doesn't unless unless the Americans can
somehow avert uh the path you know the
the Fate that awaits most Empires
through technological means like AI Etc
so yeah that's the that's that's my
perspective okay that's done I'm done
with these questions let's take for
about 10 minutes
some live chat questions Lipton barua
says about around 400 to 500 Hindu
families have arrived from Bangladesh
into the Siliguri Corridor region juluri
District the BSF stopped them what to do
now our region is also sensitive look
the BSF is under the command and under
the orders of the government of India it
is a central paramilitary Force as far
as I am aware which means they take
their orders from New
Delhi so if New Delhi has ordered the
BSF to stop anyone from crossing the
border from Bangladesh into India they
will do what they are told I wish they
had done that in the past 30
years but now they're doing
it so what can you the C people do
nothing that is the sad reality today
that Hindus will will suffer in
Bangladesh and the government will may
not do much Beyond sending a few
tweets the rest of the world is tweeting
about this some good people from various
parts of the world are tweeting about
the genocide of Hindus that's going on
in Bangladesh right now and that's uh I
don't know if the Indian government will
do anything about this
they may even like you're saying like
you're reporting they are stopping
Hindus from crossing over there is
obviously a good reason for that also
because along with those Hindus who are
crossing over some terrorists may also
cross over in the guise of Hindus there
is also a possibility so what do you do
you can take this the easy way out and
stop anybody from Crossing which means
you leave the innocent Hindus to their
fate which means they will all be killed
or you devise
ways of weeding out
the undesirables but that takes more
work
so very
very um desperate situation now for
Hindus in East Pakistan very very sad
and I really thank you Lipton barua for
reporting this the world needs to know
what's
happening
okay
um kunjan Peri says why did shik not
apply for Asylum in
Russia I don't know why why didn't she
apply for asylum in Finland or or or or
in China or let's say in Botswana I mean
you go where you are the safest first
right the one nation that has stood by
her the past 10 plus years is
India and uh yeah that's why she first
came to India she probably wanted to go
somewhere else after swapping over in
India but but the West naturally has
declined her request to travel there the
Americans have canceled her visa the
British have also said she's not welcome
so it looks like she will stay here so
and I'm not sure what the relationship
between her and the Russians and Mr
Putin was but I think she's safest in
India she has in the past been a refugee
in India when her father was killed and
her entire family was massacred in the
70s she spent five or six years in India
as a refugee in New Delhi so she's
familiar with India she has lived here
before and it's natural for her to
turn to India in the in the worst time
of her
life VII says sir will you write books
for us youngsters to help understand our
true history of civilization and
geopolitics affecting Barat you can play
a great role in in educating us
systematically yes this is something I
need to do and I will be doing that and
thank you for the reminder lots of
people are reminding me I appreciate
that and I will be writing books
yes okay
um artillery chavda says what languages
do you speak I speak I speak uh among
Indian languages I speak Hindi Gujarati
I understand lots of languages bits and
pieces I understand marati to a great
extent almost 90 95% marati I understand
I don't speak that well I understand
most other Northern Indian languages to
various degrees Punjabi Bengali
various uh dialects of Hindi Etc um so
those those are the Indian languages
foreign languages I speak English and
French and I understand various other uh
Romans languages to various degrees like
Spanish Italian I understand to a c to
to a certain extent Portuguese to a
certain extent I I I understand a bit of
Russian I understand some German so I I
have been very curious about languages
that's why I kind of have some
understanding so typically when you when
I hear someone speak a foreign language
I most likely understand what language
that is based on the accent and the
words and all
that please repeat the Gorka rles rifles
warcry was it not J mahakali AO gorali I
thought it was Kiki Soo l or something
like
that um maybe maybe something else I
don't know as far as I know that's the
one ARA Mana says what's the future of
UK riots well I hope it stops but most
likely it won't the future of the UK is
londonistan that's the
Future
Okay the just says why is the US media
why is the US media silent on Hindu
atrocities in Bangladesh what can India
do about it they're not silent the New
York Times is saying that there have
been a Revenge attacks on Hindus in
Bangladesh and the question people asked
is Revenge for
what revenge for existing and then they
removed the word Revenge from the from
the
headline yeah let's go let's go and take
a look at that yeah New York
Times
um let's see this New York Times Revenge
attacks on Hindus in
Bangladesh so New York Times labels
anti-hindu violence in Bangladesh as
Revenge Bangladesh Hindus were attacked
in Revenge screams Hindu since screams
the New York Times you go to this thing
and you will see that Hindus in
Bangladesh face attacks after Prime
Ministers exit it's it doesn't use the
word Revenge anymore so this came out
two days ago now let's let's uh custom
range
let's see August 7th to August 7th and
let's see
now New York Times changes headlines
okay I'm not sure if it's visible
here 7th
August what about 6th August is it was
it there on the 6th of
August okay I think it's it's not that
easy to discover this on on on an
American
search engine but they were terming
these attacks on Hindus as Revenge
attacks as if the Hindus have brought
this among themselves the question is
what Revenge Revenge for what revenge
for simply existing right so the US
attack the US media is now speaking
about this but they are trying to
portray this as a Justified Revenge
justifiable revenge on Hindus and if you
read that article it kind of despite
them changing the headline they're
trying to Portrait the Hindus as have
supported as having supported a
dictator so they're worse than silent
now they are taking sides and they're
trying to tell the world that the
attacks on Hindus are
Justified it's kind of like how they
alleged that the Germans Justified the
Nazis Justified Violence against Jews
the same thing they are doing right now
they are behaving like Nazis the US
media Shameless people absolutely
Shameless
okay
um mclen says do you think the reason
the government is not changing the
education system is because they don't
want the citizens to get too powerful no
that's that's the Western narrative that
what that's what happens in the west
that the government wants to control the
people in India it's because it's it's a
tough thing to do
takes too much work and there'll be too
much opposition everybody will do award
wapsi and all the intellectuals will
stand up against the government and make
a human cry the media will get involved
and foreign governments will get
involved and they will that India is
trying to saffron IE the education
system it's too much of a difficult task
let things be the way they the way they
are the system is fine the way it is the
people who are in power in the
government today they came to power
through the system because of the system
then why will they change the system and
most of them are me colonizing the
believe that the system is good
anyway that's the problem it's it's
because of low standards overall that
the education system is not being
changed
ah shti pel says should India steel
fence the whole Bangladesh border as
soon as possible just like the Pakistan
border if possible yeah but then the
question is what happens to the
Bangladeshi
Hindus do we leave them to to their fate
which is
death
uh I think what we what we can do is
instead of Steel fencing it we should
have robust border infrastructure
military and paramilitary infrastructure
so that we can prevent infiltration
without steel
fencing of course we will have to put
lots of security forces on the borders
that that may cost way more money than
steel
fencing so it's for the Indian
government to decide but my point is if
we steel fence the whole
border then the Hindus in Bangladesh are
left to their fate and they will
die soon enough you will have less than
2% Hindu population just like in
Pakistan so that is the
dilemma I think we can steel fence large
portion of the border and keep some
portions open from which people can
perhaps come into
India uh and obviously we should
repatriate now the 100 million
Bangladeshi infiltrators who live in
India see the one of the reasons in the
past 10 years that India did not send
back repatriate Deport the 100 million
Bangladesh's who are living illegally in
India is because we did not want to
destroy the Bangladeshi economy because
we needed shikh to do well and she did
well with the with the economy but now
we have a hostile government in power in
in East Pakistan we should now
identify and Deport the 100 million
illegal Bangladeshi infiltrators back to
Bangladesh I think that's what needs to
be done will the government have the
rocks to do it is the question
okay I will take one more question
because we have gone past two
hours J P says marriage was meant to
combine resources between you and your
wife to make the marriage stronger and
more resistant to shield from hardships
and have a more satisfying marriage
overall I think it's like two people
becoming one that's kind of that's kind
of how marriage was seen in India
historically today it's all you know how
it
is uh
what would happen says Shas shat if
Bangladesh invades India will it be
backed by the us if Bangladesh invades
India it will seize to exist very soon
whether it's backed by the us or not
doesn't
matter that's what I can
say and
uh
uh should I take one more
question one more question one more
question
the just says if Mr Modi had lost the
elections would we still see a regime
change in Bangladesh we may still see a
regime change in Bangladesh because
hypothetically if Mr Modi had lost the
elections in 2024 you would still have a
pro-india government in Bangladesh which
would not be acceptable to the US so
they would have still gone ahead with
the regime
change okay I think we are done for
today that's it um way past two hours so
thank you so much for all all your
questions thank you for your
participation I apologize to those of
you whose questions I could not take but
we're going to keep doing this over and
over lots of things are going to happen
in the next few weeks and I would love
to have your questions in the next live
stream which will happen uh sometime
next week so probably next week probably
three live streams let's let's try and
make it three next week so I look
forward to your questions at that time
thank you so much for everything for
your viewership for your participation
please keep raising your St
please keep asking questions and I will
see you very soon in the next live
stream thank you bye